2026 has just begun
Everyone has been bombarded by several domestic large AI models.
I worked overnight for 5 hours
conducted a comprehensive test of
their performance in complex project development
The results are completely unexpected.
After watching this video
you will know how to choose
If you don't want to watch the evaluation process
You can directly skip to the results section at the end of the video
Remember to triple-combo and follow!
From two days before the Spring Festival, DeepSeek launched the official version V3.2
supporting 1 million tokens, to the release of the GLM 5 open-source model
and MiniMax launched its new 2.5 version
What's even more exaggerated is
Qwen3.5 plus was released on New Year's Eve
setting various records
But the question is, who performs best in AI programming?
I used a practical development case to test the actual development capabilities and results.
from UI design to project completion
covering UI effects
Coding proficiency and tool invocation cost overheads
Since DeepSeek did not release the V4 version in time
This comparison will not include it
otherwise it would be unfair
The remaining three models run simultaneously, with three cloud code instances for GLM and MiniMax.
MiniMax 2.5 adopts the purchased coding plan package
Here, everyone needs to pay attention again
GLM is currently only available in Pro and Max plans, while Qwen 3.5 plus is directly paid via API.
Because its coding plan does not yet support the Qwen3.5 plus model
Qwen3.5-plus model
To ensure the fairness and validity of the comparison
We all adopt the Claude Code plus Skills mode for development.
Adopt the same requirements
including project objectives, character functionality, tech stack, and UI requirements
project structure, etc.
but each element is clear, concise, and complete
The testing process is divided into three steps
1. Prepare a parallel development environment
Install external tools on GitHub
It is slightly different from CC-Switch
It allows multiple claude code to run different models simultaneously
will not be repeated here
Here we create three directories in VS Code
namely GLM 5, Minimax 2.5, and Qwen3.5
2.5 and QW3.5
Create a docs directory in each file directory
then run the vibe command separately
Select different suppliers
and enter the corresponding ApiKey
The first one uses GLM 5
The second one uses Minimax 2.5
the third one uses Qwen3.5-plus
2 Install the corresponding skills
We will use two core skills during our development process.
UI-UX-Pro-Max and superpowers
SKILLS, the first one is to evaluate their UI design capabilities
The second is to observe their understanding of requirements
the breakdown of the plan and the comprehensive capability of product development. Let's first open the Minimax page to take a look
First, install these two skills separately
The method is very simple
Simply use the npx skills command for installation.
To supplement
Superpowers has many skills
We only have 3 here
so first directly install the required 3 skills
For other features, you can also install the complete content on Github.
Three development tests were conducted, starting with the creation of UI prototypes.
Run the following commands in the three Claude codes respectively
Start in the order of 1, 2, 3 respectively
We quickly saw Qwen 3.5 and MiniMax 2.5
quickly started the prototype development based on this skill
and informed that it would generate an interactive HTML page, while GLM 5 seemed slower
while GLM 5 seems to be slower
probably too many people are using the server
a bit underwhelming
After about 6 minutes
We can see that Mini Max has completed the UI prototype design
Then Qwen has also completed it
The UI effect looks decent
It aligns well with the Tailwind design style.
All four tab menus are clickable
each also has simulated data, with some functions being non-clickable
In contrast, Qwen's interface is much more minimalist.
It belongs to a very traditional UI prototype layout effect
The effect is acceptable
but it doesn't show a strong sense of design
We won't wait for GLM 5 to complete
Let these two with completed UI designs proceed first.
First, use the 'writing plans' skill we installed
Write the development plan
UI prototypes, as well as the versal react native skill for writing
writing native skills
At this point, both Qwen and MiniMax directly invoked the relevant skills
Start drafting the complete development plan
After the plan is completed in a moment
Let's take a look, the entire development plan is approximately 2,000 lines long.
approximately over 2,000 lines
Open the Qianwan development plan again
The generation time is slightly longer than MiniMax.
At this point, we look at GLM again, and there is still not much progress.
The API request timed out
After manually stopping it, let it continue the development
but the effect is not obvious
After the plan is written
We let it start executing the development plan
require the use of subagent-driven-development
development mode respectively
Now Qwen and MiniMax will first execute the executing-plans
Jian Plus
this feature
Automatically perform complete project development based on the organized development plan.
During the development process
Here we can clearly see the differences
Minimax located my installed oh my claude code
and directly invoked the subagent for parallel development
while Qwen did not utilize this skill
It uses the Git worktree approach for parallel development.
From this perspective
Minimax's invocation of skills and tools
seems more accurate and advanced than Qwen
compatible with some of the more popular development methods currently in use
10X acceleration in progress... In terms of the number of tasks and the development time executed
The difference is actually not significant
But one very important point
We noticed that Qianwan during the development process
repeatedly compressing the context
This is also due to the difference in their development approaches.
This results in differences in the stability and effectiveness of the development.
Mini Max, on the other hand, completes the entire development plan and tasks in one go.
but was interrupted once midway
Both completed the project development tasks
after running
Unfortunately, both encountered a failure to display correctly on the first run
bug that could not be displayed correctly
Qwen took three attempts to fix
while MiniMax took two attempts
running on ports 8,091 and 8,090 respectively
and port 8090
can directly launch the web version for interface access
Here we can see that Qwen, although it can access the login page
but it seems incomplete
does not provide mock functionality
Unable to register or log in
and thus cannot see the specific page functionalities
The API usage fees have been overdrawn
I didn't proceed any further
Mini Max after successful execution
provides mock login functionality
Click to go directly to the Home
The functionality and content of the 4 Tab menus are visible
Basically similar to the UI prototype
also has relatively abundant data support
However, there are indeed some missing details in the functionality.
I ultimately gave up on GLM 5
running the official package in Claude Code
and instead used another IDE to test the GLM5 model
the speed was not an issue
Ultimately, the entire project was successfully developed and completed.
The project still failed to run successfully
From the developed UI prototype, the aesthetics are similar to MiniMax.
The APP interface was not visible
I was really frustrated by the official server.
Regarding multimodal capabilities
The GLM 5 model does not support multimodal capabilities.
while MiniMax also requires access via MCP
to understand images
while Qwen3.5-plus natively supports multimodal capabilities
and it even surpasses the Qwen-VL model in visual capabilities
should currently be the strongest among all open-source models
Finally, let's take a look at the final performance
and the token usage
1. GLMM5, we spent a huge amount of money on the Pro version package, 1. GLM5
The result only output two or three sentences.
Unexpectedly, the backend showed a token consumption of 27%.
The official server is too unreliable.
Although we used the GLM 5 version on another platform
completed the UI prototype and project development
The cost of purchasing the plan is the highest
I really want a refund
but cannot get a refund
Everyone should be cautious.
2. MiniMax 2.5 purchased the 29-yuan package
not only completed the project development, but also achieved the fastest development speed
and the UI effect and restoration are the highest
the entire tokens
consumed only 79% of the cheapest plan quota
3. Qwen 3.5-plus currently adopts an API subscription model
The project is basically completed
The speed is not much different from Mini Max
but it performs slightly worse than MiniMax in terms of tool invocation, UI, and prototype rendering
slightly inferior to MiniMax
The project consumed over 200 million tokens
The actual API cost has a slight delay
approximately over 30 yuan
That's all for the results of my intensive testing during the Spring Festival version.
Hope this helps
Follow me to share more valuable content